Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Writings and Publications, 1911-1990 (Box 18-20)
  - Unpublished Writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell, 1911-1990
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-1967
      - Materials related to project proposals, 1950-1951, undated, Includes correspondence, notes and draft reports. (Box-folder 19/41)
      - Draft project proposals, 1937, 1951, undated (Box-folder 19/42)
      - “Asia by Ear” notes, 1959 (Box-folder 19/43)
      - Notes from Japanese language course, 1967, undated (Box-folder 19/44)
      - Notes from Lycée de jeunes Filles class, 1922-1923, In French. (Box-folder 19/45)
      - “Anecdotes in the Chronicles of Matthew Paris,” [192-], A graduate English course thesis. (Box-folder 19/46)
      - Fiction by SRC, 1923 (Box-folder 19/47)
      - Poems by SRC, 1911, [194-?] (Box-folder 19/48)
      - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box-folder 19/49)
  - Publications Written by Others (Box 20)
    Books, journals, and reports. Two items are accompanied by explanatory narratives written by SRC.
- Subject Files, 1942-1990, bulk 1950-1988 (Box 21-22)
  Correspondence, narratives, planning documents, programs, articles, clippings, and notes relating to individuals, organizations, and personal and professional interests and activities.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization, or topic.
  - Africa, 1954, 1966, 1974,1980, Correspondence, SRC narratives, and a program. (Box-folder 21/1)
  - The Boardman School Inc., 1949 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Cage, John, 1986, Materials relating to 75th birthday celebration for Cage on the Westdeutscher Rundfunk Koln in Cologne, Germany. (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Columbia University, Sixth Annual Festival of Contemporary American Music, 1950, Correspondence, program, planning materials. (Box-folder 21/4)
  - East-West Music Encounter, 1960-1961, Correspondence, program, notes, planning documents, clippings related to Henry Cowell’s trip to Japan and Iran. (Box-folder 21/5-7)
  - Friends of SRC, A-E, Obituaries and other materials relating to friends and colleagues of SRC. (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Friends of SRC, H-S, Obituaries and other materials relating to friends and colleagues of SRC. (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Gifts to libraries, 1971-1977, 1990, Materials relating to organizations receiving Cowell materials, including Library of Congress, New York State Historical Association and State University College at New Paltz. (Box-folder 21/10)
  - Harvard University, Conference on Folk Music and Ballads, 1955, Correspondence, programs, clippings, notes. (Box-folder 21/11-13)
  - Hayes, Roland, 1976 see also Container 3, Rooks, Shelby, Mostly correspondence between SRC and others regarding efforts to assist an ailing Mr. Hayes. (Box-folder 21/14)
  - Hulme, Kathryn, 1984, Correspondence to various people in effort to reach Ms. Hulme. (Box-folder 21/15)
  - International Folk Music Council, 1955-1979, Conference programs. (Box-folder 21/16)
  - Iran see East-West Music Encounter
  - Ives, Charles, 1967-1988 see also Container 1, Bronson, Bertrand see also Containers 1-2, Hitchcock, H. Wiley see also Container 2, Kirkpatrick, John, Correspondence, narratives, articles, clippings. (Box-folder 21/17-18)
  - Japan see East-West Music Encounter
  - Letters of introduction, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Mills College, 1944, 1950, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Pan American Union, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Photography of SRC, 1962-1965 see also Photographs Series (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Ross, James, [195-?], Letter from Mr. Ross and two works that he wrote: “The Sub-Literary Tradition in Scottish Gaelic Song-Poetry” and ”A Classification of Gaelic Folksong.” (Box-folder 22/5-6)
  - Saylor, Bruce, 1975-1976 see also Container 3, Saylor, Bruce (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Spackman, Stephen, 1978-1983, undated (Box-folder 22/8-9)
  - University of Southern California, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box-folder 22/11)
- Photographs (Box 26-28)
  Chiefly black and white photographs of Sidney Robertson Cowell; Henry Cowell; their families; friends and colleagues in the music world; and musicians and performers that Sidney Robertson Cowell recorded throughout her career. Many of the photographs in this series were taken by Sidney Robertson Cowell. Includes artistic photographs taken by Cowell as well as photographs of the California Folk Music Project staff and offices.
  - Sidney Robertson Cowell alone, as a child and young girl, Sixteen black and white photographs (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Sidney Robertson Cowell, alone, as an adult, Seventeen black and white photographs; One color photograph; One negative (Box-folder 26/1-2)
  - Sidney Robertson Cowell with others, Sixteen black and white photographs (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Sidney Robertson Cowell with Henry Cowell, Four black and white photographs (some with other people) (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Henry Cowell alone, Twenty-three black and white photographs (Box-folder 26/3-4)
  - Henry Cowell with others, Eleven black and white photographs (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Sidney Robertson Cowell’s family, Twelve black and white photographs; One color photograph of Cowell house in Shady, N.Y. (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Individuals and groups, Seventy-one black and white photographs; Notables from the music world; performers that SRC recorded; and others. (Box-folder 26/6-9)
  - California Folk Music Project (some with Sidney Robertson Cowell), Ten black and white photographs; Photographs taken by Sidney Robertson Cowell. (Box-folder 26/9-10)
  - Street scenes, photo from plane, Ernest Bloch death mask, African people and musicians, Thirteen black and white photographs; Three negative strips (two photos from the negatives are in this file) (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Natural scenes, landscapes, Seven black and white photographs (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Street scenes, landscapes, nature shots, Seventeen black and white photographs (Box-folder 27/3)
  - SRC’s cats, Twenty-six black and white photographs (Box-folder 27/4)
  - SRC’s cats, animal shots, abstract shots, Sixteen black and white photographs (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Miscellaneous oversize photographs, Seven black and white photographs; All taken by SRC, except for one of SRC as a baby. (Box 28)
- Teaching Materials, 1948-1959 (Box 22-23)
  Notes, outlines, song sheets, reports and narratives relating to courses Cowell taught.
  - Teaching materials for Hamilton School, 1948, Notes, outlines, song sheets, curriculum information for teaching children music and an outline for a play. (Box-folder 22/12-14)
  - Music for Young Children, 1951, undated, Training materials, including notes, reports, narratives. (Box-folder 22/15-23)
  - Teaching materials for course on rhythm at the New School, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 23/1-13)
- Songs and Song Books (Box 24-25)
  Some songs set to music, others include lyrics only. Includes single song sheets, sheets with multiple songs, and the following groupings: songs with piano settings by Henry Cowell, protest and propaganda songs of the 1930s-1940s, and songs collected from Cinderella Kinnaird.
  Single song sheets are arranged alphabetically by song title. Protest and propaganda songs and Kinnaird’s songs are arranged alphabetically by song title within those groupings.
  - Folk songs, some with piano settings by Henry Cowell (Box-folder 24/1-21)
  - Miscellaneous songs, A-B (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Miscellaneous songs, C-D (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Miscellaneous songs, E-G (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Miscellaneous songs, H-I (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Miscellaneous songs, J-K (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Miscellaneous songs, L-M (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Miscellaneous songs, N-O (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Miscellaneous songs, P-R (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Miscellaneous songs, S (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Miscellaneous songs, T-U (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Miscellaneous songs, V-W (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Miscellaneous songs, X-Z (Box-folder 25/12)
  - Miscellaneous songs, multiple songs per sheet (Box-folder 25/13)
  - Unidentified songs (Box-folder 25/14)
  - Miscellaneous song material (Box-folder 25/15)
  - Mrs. Kinnaird’s songs, 1937 (Box-folder 25/16)
  - Protest /Propaganda songs of the 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 25/17)
  - Potamkin, Harry Alan. Pioneer Song Book: Songs for Workers’ and Farmers’ Children. New York: New Pioneer, 1933 (Box-folder 25/18)
  - “Song Book: New York City School for Workers,” 1934 (Box-folder 25/19)
  - International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union song sheets, undated (Box-folder 25/20)